[man's voice] Once upon a time in a kingdom far, far away,
很久以前，在一个遥远的王国里
the king and queen were blessed with a beautiful baby girl.
国王和王后有个美丽的公主
And throughout the land, everyone was happy...
全国上下，人人都很幸福
until the sun went down
直到太阳下山
and they saw that their daughter was cursed with a frightful enchantment
他们看见女儿受到了可怕妖术诅咒
that took hold each and every night.
每晚都是如此
Desperate, they sought the help of a fairy godmother
情急之下 他们向一位神仙教母求救
who had them lock the young princess away in a tower,
她让他们将公主关在塔楼里 等待那...
there to await the kiss... of the handsome Prince Charming.
白马王子的吻
It was he who would chance the perilous journey
只有他能够不怕旅途危险
through blistering cold and scorching desert
穿越刺骨寒冷的沙漠
traveling for many days and nights,
经过几天几夜
risking life and limb
冒着生命危险
to reach the Dragon's keep.
去找龙
For he was the bravest,
因为他是最勇敢的
and most handsome...
最英俊的
in all the land.
在全国之内
And it was destiny that his kiss
他的一个亲吻
would break the dreaded curse.
能够打破恶毒的诅咒
He alone would climb to the highest room of the tallest tower
他还要爬上塔楼最高的屋顶
to enter the princess's chambers, cross the room to her sleeping silhouette,
进入公主行宫，穿过房间 找到熟睡的侧影
pull back the gossamer curtains to find her... [gasps]
拉开薄纱窗帘找到她
What?
什么？
- Princess... Fiona? - No!
- 费欧娜公主？ - 不!
[sighs relief] Oh, thank heavens. Where is she?
谢天谢地，她在哪里？
- She's on her honeymoon. - Honeymoon? With whom?
- 她在度蜜月 - 蜜月？跟谁在一起？
* So she said what's the problem, baby?
* What's the problem? I don't know
* Well, maybe I'm in love
* Think about it every time I think 'bout it
* Can't stop thinking 'bout it * How much longer will it take to cure this?
“亨瑟的蜜月小屋”
* Just to cure it, 'cause I can't ignore it
* If it's love, love
* Makes me wanna turn around and face me
* But I don't know nothing 'bout love
* Oh, come on, come on
- [screams] - * Turn a little faster
* Come on, come on
* The world will follow after
* Everybody's after love
* So I said I'm a snowball running
* Running down into this spring that's coming all this love
* Melting under blue skies belting out sunlight
* Shimmering love
* Well, baby, I surrender
* To the strawberry ice cream
* Never ever end of all this love
* Well, I didn't mean to do it
“我爱你”
* But there's no escaping your love
* These lines of lightning mean we're never alone
* Never alone, no, no
* Come on, come on
* Jump a little higher
* If you feel a little lighter
* Come on, come on
* We were once upon a time in love
* We're accidentally in love
* Accidentally in love
* Accidentally
* I'm in love, I'm in love, I'm in love, I'm in love
* I'm in love, I'm in love
* Accidentally in love
* I'm in love
* I'm in love *
lt's so good to be home!
回家的感觉真好
“小心妖怪”
Just you and me and...
只有你和我
- * Two can be as bad as one... * - Donkey?
两个可以跟一个一样糟糕
Shrek! Fiona! Aren't you two a sight for sore eyes!
史莱克!费欧娜! 你们两个太过分了吧
Give us a hug, Shrek, you old love machine.
搂一下我，你的老情人
[chuckles] And look at you, Mrs. Shrek. How 'bout a side of sugar for the steed?
看你，史莱克太太 给老朋友一个香吻
Donkey, what are you doing here?
驴子，你在这里做什么？
Taking care of your love nest for you.
帮你照看爱巢
Oh, you mean like... sorting the mail and watering the plants?
你的意思是 分类邮件，并给花浇水
- Yeah, and feeding the fish! - l don't have any fish.
- 还要喂鱼! - 我没有鱼
You do now. l call that one Shrek and the other Fiona.
现在有了，名叫史莱克和费欧娜
That Shrek is a rascally devil. Get your...
那史莱克是个大坏蛋
Look at the time. l guess you'd better be going.
看看时间，你该走了
Don't you want to tell me about your trip? Or how about a game of Parcheesi?
等等，你不想告诉我 你旅行的事吗？ 玩双骰子游戏如何？
Actually, Donkey? Shouldn't you be getting home to Dragon?
其实，驴子 你不要回家找小龙女吗？
Oh, yeah, that.
对了，那个
l don't know. She's been all moody and stuff lately.
不知道，她最近非常情绪化
l thought l'd move in with you.
我不如搬来跟你们一起住吧
You know we're always happy to see you, Donkey.
我们能见到你很高兴
But Fiona and l are married now.
但是费欧娜和我现在已经结婚了
We need a little time, you know, to be together.
我们需要时间相处
Just with each other.
二人世界
Alone.
独处
Say no more. You don't have to worry about a thing.
不要再说了，你不需要担心什么的
l will always be here to make sure nobody bothers you.
我一定会确保没有人来打扰你们
- Donkey! - Yes, roomie?
- 驴子 - 好吧，室友
You're bothering me.
你打扰了我们
Oh, OK. All right, cool. l guess...
好吧，这样吧
Me and Pinocchio was going to catch a tournament, anyway, so...
我和小木偶正要去看比赛
Maybe l'll see y'all Sunday for a barbecue or something.
星期天见
He'll be fine. Now, where were we?
他会没事的，我们刚才说到哪里？
l think l remember.
我记起了
- Donkey! - [Fiona yelps]
驴子!
l know, l know! Alone! l'm going! l'm going.
我知道，独处 我走了，马上走!
What do you want me to tell these other guys?
你要我告诉他们什么？
Enough, Reggie.
够了，瑞琪
[clears throat] ''Dearest Princess Fiona.
最亲爱的费欧娜公主
''You are hereby summoned to the Kingdom of Far, Far Away
你被召见来远的要命王国
''for a royal ball in celebration of your marriage
以盛大舞会庆祝你的婚礼
''at which time the King
在此国王
''will bestow his royal blessing...
会赐予他的祝福
upon you and your...''
向你和你的
uh... ''Prince Charming.
白马王子
''Love, the King and Queen of Far, Far Away.
爱你的远的要命王国的国王王后
''aka Mom and Dad.''
也是你的妈妈爸爸
Mom and Dad?
妈妈爸爸？
- Prince Charming? - Royal ball? Can l come?
- 白马王子？ - 我能去吗？
- We're not going. - [both] What?
- 我们不去 - 什么？
l mean, don't you think they might be a bit...
你不觉得他们
shocked to see you like this?
见到你这样会惊奇？
[chuckles] Well, they might be a bit surprised.
他们也许会惊奇
But they're my parents, Shrek. They love me.
但他们是我的父母，他们爱我
And don't worry. They'll love you, too.
别担心，他们也会爱你的
Yeah, right. Somehow l don't think l'll be welcome at the country club.
我不认识的人会在乡村俱乐部欢迎
Stop it. They're not like that.
别这样，他们不会那样的
How do you explain Sergeant Pompous and the Fancy Pants Club Band?
你怎么解释那次号手乐队？
Oh, come on! You could at least give them a chance.
算了，就给他们一次机会吧
To do what? Sharpen their pitchforks?
做什么？磨利他们的刀叉
No! They just want to give you their blessing.
不!他们只是想祝福你而已
Oh, great. Now l need their blessing?
真好，我现在倒希望得到祝福？
lf you want to be a part of this family, yes!
如果你希望成为这个家庭一员的话
Who says l want to be part of this family?
谁说我想成为这个家庭一员？
You did! When you married me!
你娶了我时就想
Well, there's some fine print for you!
这个我倒没想到
[exasperated sigh] So that's it. You won't come?
那么你不想来了
Trust me. lt's a bad idea. We are not going! And that's final!
相信我，肯定是坏主意 我们坚决不去
Come on! We don't want to hit traffic!
快来!这样就不会遇到交通阻塞
[Gingy] Don't worry! We'll take care of everything.
别担心，我们会帮你搞定
- Hey, wait for me. Oof! - [glass breaks]
嘿，等等我
* Hit it! Move 'em on! Head 'em up! Head 'em up, move 'em on! Head 'em up!
快走，快走，快点走！ 快走，快走，快点走！
* Rawhide! Move 'em on! Head 'em up!
快行快行快快行！
* Move 'em on! Move 'em on! Head 'em up! Rawhide!
* Ride 'em up! Move 'em on! Head 'em up! Move 'em on! Rawhide!
快快走！
* Knock 'em out! Pound 'em dead! Make 'em tea! Buy 'em drinks!
快快走！快快行！ 喝茶！喝汽水！
* Meet their mamas! Milk 'em hard! * Rawhide! * Yee-haw!
见见老妈妈！用力挤奶！
远的要命王国，700英里
- [Donkey] Are we there yet? - [Shrek] No.
- 我们到了吗？ - 还没有
- [Donkey] Are we there yet? - [Fiona] Not yet.
- 到了没有？ - 还没有
远的要命王国，200英里
- [Donkey] OK, are we there yet? - [Fiona] No.
- 到了没有？ - 没有
- [Donkey] Are we there yet? - [Shrek] No!
- [Donkey] Are we there yet? - [Shrek] Yes.
- 到了没有啊？ - 到了
- Really? - No!
- 真的？ - 不!
- Are we there yet? - [Fiona] No!
- 到了没有啊？ - 没有!
- Are we there yet? - [Shrek] We are not!
- 到了没有啊？ - 没有!   远的要命王国，100英里
- Are we there yet? - [Shrek & Fiona] No!
- 到了没有？ - 没有!
- Are we there yet? - [Shrek mimics]
- 到了没有？不是好玩的 - 到了没有？不是好玩的
- That's not funny. That's really immature. - [Shrek mimics]
- 真是幼稚 - 的确幼稚
- This is why nobody likes ogres. - [Shrek mimics]
- 所以没人喜欢怪物 - 所以没人喜欢怪物
- Your loss! - [Shrek mimics]
好!你输了! 我不讲话
- l'm gonna just stop talking. - Finally!
好，你输了 总算是
This is taking forever, Shrek. There's no in-flight movie or nothing!
但这样很久，没有舱内电影
The Kingdom of Far, Far Away, Donkey.
远的要命王国，驴子
That's where we're going. Far, far...
我们就要去那里
[softly] away!
遥远
All right, all right, l get it. l'm just so darn bored.
好吧，明白了，我不过觉得无聊
Well, find a way to entertain yourself.
设法自己娱乐吧
For five minutes...
5分钟
Could you not be yourself... [shouts] ...for five minutes!
能不能坚持5分钟？
Are we there yet?
到了没有？
- [chuckles] Yes! - Oh, finally!
- 到了! - 总算到了!
新婚
欢迎来到远的要命王国
Wow!
哇!
lt's going to be champagne wishes and caviar dreams from now on.
肯定会有香槟酒鱼子酱招待哦
Hey, good-looking! We'll be back to pick you up later!
漂亮!我们一会儿来接你!
* Gotta make a move to a town that's right for me
连裤丝袜 幸福生活神仙教母
We are definitely not in the swamp anymore.
我们肯定不会在烂泥潭里
[whistle] Halt!
停
* Well, I talk about it, talk about it, talk about it, talk about it
Hey, everyone, look.
大家快看
* Talk about, talk about movin'... *
Hey, ladies! Nice day for a parade, huh?
大家快看! 小姐们!出来游行的好天气呀!
You working that hat.
帽子好漂亮!
长发公主
灰姑娘
[Donkey] Swimming pools! Movie stars!
游泳池!电影明星!
远的要命王国
Announcing the long-awaited return
宣告国人等待已久的
of the beautiful Princess Fiona and her new husband.
美丽公主费欧娜和新婚丈夫的回归
Well, this is it.
就是这里
- This is it. - This is it.
- 就是这个 - 就是这个
This is it.
就是这个
Uh... why don't you guys go ahead? l'll park the car.
你们先去，我来停车
[chuckles] So... you still think this was a good idea?
你仍觉得这是个好主意
Of course! Look. Mom and Dad look happy to see us.
当然，妈妈爸爸很高兴见到我们
- [softly] Who on earth are they? - [softly] l think that's our little girl.
- 他们是谁？ - 那个就是我们的小女儿
That's not little! That's a really big problem.
她可不小啊，而且有个大问题
Wasn't she supposed to kiss Prince Charming and break the spell?
她不应该去亲吻 白马王子并打破咒语？
Well, he's no Prince Charming, but they do look...
不过他不是白马王子，不过他们
[softly] Happy now? We came. We saw them.
高兴了？我们来了，看见他们了
Now let's go before they light the torches.
趁他们还没有点亮火炬快跑
- They're my parents. - Hello? They locked you in a tower.
- 他们是我的父母 - 他们把你锁在塔楼里
That was for my own...
不过是为我
Good! Here's our chance. Let's go back inside and pretend we're not home.
为你好？这是我们的机会 我们进去假装没有在家
Harold, we have to be...
哈洛，我们要假装
Quick! While they're not looking we can make a run for it.
快点 趁他们没看，我们赶快跑
Shrek, stop it! Everything's gonna be...
够了!一切都会
A disaster! There is no way...
变成灾难，根本不可能
- You can do this. - l really...
- 你能行 - 但我实在
- Really... - don't...
- 真的 - 真的
want... to... be...
- 不要 - 我想
Here!
- 安静 - 这里
Mom...
妈妈!
Dad...
爸爸!
l'd like you to meet my husband...
这是我的丈夫
Shrek.
史莱克!
lt's easy to see where Fiona gets her good looks from.
不难看出费欧娜的美貌源自何处
- Excuse me. - [Shrek & Fiona laugh]
对不起
Better out than in, l always say, eh, Fiona?
我总说出来总比藏在肚里好
[Shrek] That's good.
很好
l guess not. What do you mean, ''not on the list''? Don't tell me you don't know who l am. What do you mean,
我看不会 不在名单上是什么意思？ 别说你不认识我
What's happening, everybody? Thanks for waiting.
大家好啊？ 多谢等候
- l had the hardest time finding this place
要找到这里真不容易
- No! No! Bad donkey! Bad! Down!
不!坏驴子!坏蛋!蹲下!
No, Dad! lt's all right. lt's all right. He's with us.
爸爸，没事，他跟我们一起来的
- He helped rescue me from the dragon. - That's me: the noble steed.
- 他从小龙女的手下解救了我们 - 那就是我，皇家战马
Waiter! How 'bout a bowl for the steed?
招待，给本战马来只碗如何？
Oh, boy.
哎哟
- Um, Shrek? - Yeah?
史莱克
Oh, sorry! Great soup, Mrs Q.
抱歉!汤很好喝，王后太太
No, no. Darling.
不，亲爱的
So, Fiona, tell us about where you live.
费欧娜，告诉我们你住的地方
Shrek owns his own land.
史莱克有自己的地
- Don't you, honey? - Oh, yes!
- 对吧，亲爱的？ - 当然了
lt's in an enchanted forest
是个充满魔法的森林
abundant in squirrels and cute little duckies and...
到处都是小松鼠和可爱的小鸭子
[laughing] What? l know you ain't talking about the swamp.
什么？你不是在谈沼泽吧？
An ogre from a swamp. Oh! How original.
沼泽地里来的怪物 见怪不怪吧
l suppose that would be a fine place to raise the children.
那种地方养孩子应该不错吧
lt's a bit early to be thinking about that, isn't it?
现在想那种事有点过早吧？
- lndeed. l just started eating. - Harold!
- 的确，我刚才开始吃 - 哈洛
- What's that supposed to mean? - Dad. lt's great, OK?
- 这是什么意思？ - 爸爸，一切都好
- For his type, yes. - My type?
- 对于这种，算是吧 - 我这种？
l got to go to the bathroom.
我要上厕所
- Dinner is served! - Never mind. l can hold it.
- 晚餐伺候! - 没关系，我能忍住
Bon appetit!
- 慢慢用
Oh, Mexican food! My favorite.
- 墨西哥菜，我最喜欢的
Let's not sit here with our tummies rumbling. Everybody dig in.
大家别坐着挨饿，快吃吧
Don't mind if l do, Lillian.
不介意我也吃吧，莉雅
l suppose any grandchildren l could expect from you would be...
你觉得我的任何孙子都会是
Ogres, yes!
怪模怪样!
Not that there's anything wrong with that. Right, Harold?
也算不上什么大问题 对吧，哈洛
Oh, no! No! Of course, not!
当然不算
That is, assuming you don't eat your own young!
不过，你不吃自己的孩子吧？
Dad!
爸爸
No, we usually prefer the ones who've been locked away in a tower!
不会，我们比较喜欢 吃被锁在塔楼里的
- Shrek, please! - l only did that because l love her.
- 史莱克，够了 - 我完全出于爱她
Aye, day care or dragon-guarded castle.
对呀，托儿所或者是 小龙女看守的城堡
You wouldn't understand. You're not her father!
你不明白，你不是她父亲
lt's so nice to have the family together for dinner.
一家人一起吃饭真好
- Harold! - Shrek!
- 哈洛! - 史莱克!
- Fiona! - Fiona!
- 费欧娜! - 费欧娜!
- Mom! - Harold...
- 妈妈! - 哈洛!
Donkey!
驴子
* Your fallen tears have called to me
你的眼泪召唤我来
* So, here comes my sweet remedy
我带来我甜蜜的疗法
* I know what every princess needs
我知道每个公主所需要的
* For her to live life happily... *
为了能让她幸福生活
Oh, my dear. Oh, look at you.
亲爱的，看看你
You're all grown up.
你已完全长大
- Who are you? - Oh, sweet pea!
- 你是谁？ - 小甜甜
l'm your fairy godmother.
我是你的神仙教母
- l have a fairy godmother? - Shush, shush.
我有神仙教母？
Now, don't worry. l'm here to make it all better.
别担心，我是来帮你的
With just a...
只要一点点
* Wave of my magic wand Your troubles will soon be gone
轻挥我的魔术棒 你的烦恼全不见
* With a flick of the wrist and just a flash You'll land a prince with a ton of cash
轻轻一转，你就会赢得王子
* A high-priced dress made by mice no less
高级手工制作的昂贵裙子
* Some crystal glass pumps And no more stress
享用水晶杯再也没有烦恼
* Your worries will vanish, your soul will cleanse
所有烦恼全不见，灵魂洁净又轻松
* Confide in your very own furniture friends
给你找到知心朋友
* We'll help you set a new fashion trend
我们帮你设立最新时尚潮流
- * I'll make you fancy, I'll make you great - * The kind of girl a prince would date!
- 我能把你变成天仙 - 变成每个王子梦寐以求的女孩
* They'll write your name on the bathroom wall...
他们会把你的名字写在厕所墙上
* ''For a happy ever after, give Fiona a call!''
要想得到永久的幸福 打电话找费欧娜
* A sporty carriage to ride in style, Sexy man boy chauffeur, Kyle
骑上的跑车型、的马车 性感男生司机，凯尔
* Banish your blemishes, tooth decay, Cellulite thighs will fade away
改头换面，打造新人 再来只宠物狗
* And oh, what the hey! Have a bichon frise!'
整形手术，全身动作
* Nip and tuck, here and there to land that prince with the perfect hair
丝滑的头发赢得王子心
* Lipstick liners, shadows blush To get that prince with the sexy tush
化妆品样样来 赢得性感小王子的心
* Lucky day, hunk buffet You and your prince take a roll in the hay
要走运，钓帅哥 和你的王子干草堆上滚一圈
* You can spoon on the moon With the prince to the tune
肯定会乐得你飞上天
够了!
* Don't be drab, you'll be fab Your prince will have rock-hard abs
别老土了 你们肯定会郎才女貌天仙配
* Cheese souffle, Valentine's Day Have some chicken fricassee!
情人节里享用浪漫大餐
* Nip and tuck, here and there To land that prince with the perfect hair *
修修整整这里那里 白马王子美发飘飘
Stop!
其实
[chuckles] Look... Thank you very much, Fairy Godmother,
多谢了，神仙教母
but l really don't need all this.
可我真不需要这些
- Fine. Be that way. - We didn't like you, anyway. - [knocking] - [Shrek] Fiona? Fiona?
- 好吧，随你吧 - 我们反正不喜欢你
Oh! You got a puppy? All l got in my room was shampoo.
你有小狗？ 我的房间里只有洗发水
Fairy Godmother, furniture...
神仙教母，砭
l'd like you to meet my husband, Shrek.
来见见我的丈夫，史莱克
Your husband? What? What did you say? When did this happen?
你的丈夫？ 你说什么？几时的事？
Shrek is the one who rescued me.
史莱克是拯救我的人
- But that can't be right. - Oh, great, more relatives!
- 不可能的 - 太好了，更多亲戚反对
She's just trying to help.
她只想帮忙而已
Good! She can help us pack. Get your coat, dear. We're leaving.
好!她可以帮我们收拾行李 快拿衣服，我们走
- What? - l don't want to leave.
- 什么？ - 走？我不想走
When did you decide this?
你几时决定的？
- Shortly after arriving. - Look, l'm sorry...
- 刚到不久 - 抱歉
No, that's all right. l need to go, anyway.
没关系 反正我也要走了
But remember, dear. lf you should ever need me...
记住，亲爱的 如果你需要我的话
happiness... is just a teardrop away.
幸福只需要一滴眼泪
Thanks, but we've got all the happiness we need.
多谢了，但我们已经够幸福了
Happy, happy, happy...
幸福，幸福，幸福...
[laughs] So l see. Let's go, Kyle.
明白了，我们走，凯尔
- Very nice, Shrek. - What?
- 很好，史莱克 - 什么？
l told you coming here was a bad idea.
我说过来这里不是好主意
You could've at least tried to get along with my father.
你根本没有尝试跟我父亲相处
l don't think l was going to get Daddy's blessing, even if l did want it.
我觉得根本得不到你老爸的祝福
Do you think it might be nice if somebody asked me what l wanted?
即使我很想得到 要是有人问我的意见就好了
Sure. Do you want me to pack for you?
当然，你要我帮你收拾行李吗？
You're unbelievable! You're behaving like a...
你简直不可理喻，行为举止就像
- Go on! Say it! - Like an ogre!
- 说呀! - 简直像怪物
Here's a news flash for you!
最新消息是
Whether your parents like it or not... l am an ogre!
无论你父母喜不喜欢 我都是怪物
And guess what, Princess? That's not about to change.
而且，公主殿下，这不会改变的
l've made changes for you, Shrek. Think about that.
我已经为你改变了自己，史莱克
That's real smooth, Shrek. ''l'm an ogre!''
你真行，史莱克，我是怪物
l knew this would happen. [Lillian] You should. You started it.
- 我就知道会这样 - 你应该，是你引发的
l can hardly believe that, Lillian. He's the ogre. Not me.
我不能相信，莉雅，真的 他是怪物，又不是我
l think, Harold, you're taking this a little too personally.
我觉得，哈洛 你反应太过分
This is Fiona's choice.
- 这是费欧娜的选择 - 不错!
But she was supposed to choose the prince we picked for her.
她应选中我们替她找的王子
l mean, you expect me to give my blessings to this... thing?
你想让我祝福这个 东西？
Fiona does. And she'll never forgive you if you don't.
费欧娜希望 否则她不会原谅你的
l don't want to lose our daughter again, Harold.
我不想再失去我们的女儿
Oh, you act as if love is totally predictable.
你难道认为爱情是可以预测的
Don't you remember when we were young?
你不记得我们年轻时
We used to walk down by the lily pond and...
沿着荷花池的小路走下
- they were in bloom... - Our first kiss.
- 荷花开放 - 我们的初吻
lt's not the same!
那不一样
l don't think you realize that our daughter has married a monster!
你难道不明白 我们的女儿嫁给怪物!
Oh, stop being such a drama king.
不要那么戏剧化
Fine! Pretend there's nothing wrong!
好吧!假装一切正常
La, di, da, di, da! lsn't it all wonderful! l'd like to know how it could get any worse!
这样不好么! 我倒想看看怎么会更糟
- Hello, Harold. - [gasps]
- 你好，哈洛! - 什么事？
- What happened? - Nothing, dear! Just the old hunting wound playing up a bit!
没什么 只是东征伤口有点作痛
[chuckles] l'll just stretch it out here for a while.
伸展一下就好了
You better get in. We need to talk.
你最好进来，我们要谈一谈
Actually, Fairy Godmother, off to bed.
其实，神仙教母，我正要去睡觉呢
[yawns] Already taken my pills, and they tend to make me a bit drowsy.
刚服过药，觉得有点晕晕的
So, how about... we make this a quick visit. What?
如何呢 我们速战速决吧
Oh, hello. Ha-ha-ha!
你好
So, what's new?
有什么好消息？
You remember my son, Prince Charming?
你记得我儿子白马王子吧？
ls that you? My gosh! lt's been years.
是你啊？天哪!
When did you get back?
好多年不见了，几时回来的？
Oh, about five minutes ago, actually.
大约五分钟前
After l endured blistering winds, scorching desert...
我征服了呼啸的狂风，炎热的沙漠
l climbed to the highest room in the tallest tower...
爬上了最高塔楼里最高的房间
Mommy can handle this.
妈妈能讲这个故事
He endures blistering winds and scorching desert!
他征服了呼啸的狂风，炎热的沙漠
He climbs to the highest bloody room of the tallest bloody tower...
他爬上了最高塔楼的最高房间
And what does he find?
但是 他找到了什么？
Some gender-confused wolf telling him that his princess
不男不女的大老狼说公主
is already married.
请让我 已经结婚了
lt wasn't my fault. He didn't get there in time.
不能怪我，他没有及时赶到
Stop the car!
停车!
Harold.
哈洛
You force me to do something l really don't want to do.
你要强迫我做我不愿做的事
[gasps] Where are we?
我们讲到哪里了？
Hi. Welcome to Friar's Fat Boy! May l take your order?
你好!欢迎光临肥仔速食!请点菜
My diet is ruined! l hope you're happy. Er... okay.
我的饮食结构 都被你毁了，你高兴了？
Two Renaissance Wraps, no mayo... chili rings...
两个文艺复兴卷饼 辣椒卷
- l'll have the Medieval Meal. - One Medieval Meal and, Harold...
- 我要中世记餐 - 一个中世记餐，哈洛，炸薯条？
- Curly fries? - No, thank you.
不必，谢谢了
- Sourdough soft taco, then? - No, really, l'm fine.
卷肉饼呢？ 你到底要什么？
不必了，谢谢
Your order, Fairy Godmother. This comes with the Medieval Meal.
您要的菜，神仙教母 这是中世记餐
There you are, dear.
给你，亲爱的
肥仔速食
We made a deal, Harold, and l assume you don't want me to go back on my part.
我们讲好的，哈洛 你不希望我食言吧？
[sighs deeply] lndeed not.
不要
So, Fiona and Charming will be together.
那么费欧娜要和白马王子在一起
- Yes. - Believe me, Harold. lt's what's best.
- 好的 - 相信我，哈洛
Not only for your daughter...
这样最好，不光是为了你女儿
but for your Kingdom.
也是为了你的王国
What am l supposed to do about it?
那我应该怎么办呢？
Use your imagination.
使用你的想像力
毒苹果酒吧
Come on in, Your Majesty.
进来吧，陛下
* I like my town
我喜欢我的家乡
* With a little drop of poison
一小滴毒液
* Nobody knows...
没有人知道
[clears throat] Excuse me.
对不起
Do l know you?
我认识你吗？
No, you must be mistaking me for someone else.
你肯定认错人了
Uh... excuse me. l'm looking for the Ugly Stepsister.
对不起，我在找后母生的 丑八怪灰姑娘的丑姐姐
Ah! There you are. Right.
你在这里，好了
You see, l need to have someone taken care of.
我需要把某一个人解决了
- Who's the guy? - Well, he's not a guy, per se.
- 这个人是谁？ - 其实，他不是人
Um... He's an ogre.
它是怪物
Hey, buddy, let me clue you in.
老兄，我来告诉你真相
There's only one fellow who can handle a job like that, and, frankly...
只有一个人能够应付这种事
he don't like to be disturbed.
他不喜欢别人去找他
he don't like to be disturbed. Where could l find him?
我到哪里去找他？
Hello?
喂？
Who dares enter my room?
谁敢进我的房间？
Sorry! l hope l'm not interrupting, but l'm told you're the one to talk to
抱歉!希望我没有打扰
about an ogre problem?
别人对我说你是负责怪物的
You are told correct.
说的没错
But for this, l charge a great deal of money.
但为这个，我要收取很高报酬
Would... this be enough?
这个够吗？
You have engaged my valuable services, Your Majesty.
您能够得到我的珍贵服务，陛下
Just tell me where l can find this ogre.
告诉我在哪里可以找到怪物？
* Everyone says I'm getting down too low
* Everyone says you've just gotta let it go
札斯廷阁下
* You just gotta let it go
* I need some sleep
* Time to put the old horse down
* I'm in too deep
* And the wheels keep spinning round
* Everyone says you've just gotta let it go *
Dear Knight, I pray that you take this favor as a token of my gratitude.
亲爱的骑士 我祈祷你把这个当作我的感谢
日记
Dear Diary...
亲爱的日记
Sleeping Beauty is having a slumber party tomorrow,
睡美人明天要开睡衣晚会
but Dad says I can't go. He never lets me out after sunset.
但是爸爸不让我去 他从来不让我日落后出门
Dad says I'm going away for a while.
爸爸说我要出去一阵子
Must be like some finishing school.
一定是像钓鱼学校什么的
Mom says that when I'm old enough,
妈妈说等我长大些
my Prince Charming will rescue me from my tower and bring me back to my family,
白马王子会营救我带我回家
and we'll all live happily ever after.
我们会从此幸福快乐的在一起
Mrs. Fiona Charming.
白马王子太太
Mrs. Fiona Charming. [echoing] Mrs. Fiona Charming.
Sorry. l hope l'm not interrupting anything.
抱歉，希望我没有打扰你
No, no. l was just reading a, uh... a scary book.
没有 我正在看恐怖小说
l was hoping you'd let me apologize for my despicable behavior earlier.
我想为我的不恰当行为道歉
- Okay...
好吧
- l don't know what came over me.
我不知道自己怎么搞的
Do you suppose we could pretend it never happened and start over...
不知能不能假装那种事没发生过
- Look, Your Majesty, l just... - Please. Call me Dad.
- 陛下，我只是 - 请叫我爸爸
Dad. We both acted like ogres.
爸爸，我们都缺乏文明举止
Maybe we just need some time to get to know each other.
也许我们需要一点时间互相了解
Excellent idea! l was actually hoping you might join me for a morning hunt.
好主意，不知你 是否愿意跟我一起去打猎
A little father-son time?
一点父子相处的时间
l know it would mean the world to Fiona.
费欧娜肯定会很高兴
Shall we say, 7:30 by the old oak?
明早7：30在老橡树旁
[Shrek] Face it, Donkey! We're lost.
承认吧，驴子，我们失败了
We can't be lost. We followed the King's instructions exactly.
我们不能失败 我们一字不差地听从国王的指示
What's did he say
他说什么？
''Head to the darkest part of the woods...''
- 朝向丛林的最深，最黑暗处 - 对
''Past the sinister trees with scary-looking branches.''
走过邪恶之树 那些长着恐怖模样的枝杈
Check
检查
- The bush shaped like Shirley Bassey! - We passed that three times already!
- 那些像雪丽巴瑟的树林 - 我们已经越过三次了
You were the one who said not to stop for directions.
是你说的不要停下来
Oh, great. My one chance to fix things up with Fiona's dad
很好，这是我唯一 与老岳父搞好关系的机会
and l end up lost in the woods with you!
让我在树林里跟着你迷路了
Don't get huffy! l'm only trying to help.
别那么大脾气，我不过想帮你罢了
l know! l know.
我知道!
- l'm sorry, all right? - Hey, don't worry about it.
- 抱歉了 - 别介意
l just really need to make things work with this guy.
我很想跟他建立友好关系
Yeah, sure. Now let's go bond with Daddy.
当然，我们跟老爸努力建立关系
Well, well, well, Donkey.
驴子
l know it was kind of a tender moment back there, but the purring?
我知道他温柔动人 不过故意发出噪音？
What? l ain't purring.
你讲什么？我没乱吵
Sure. What's next? A hug?
下来拥抱吗？
Hey, Shrek. Donkeys don't purr. What do you think l am, some kind of a...
驴子不会那样，你以为我是什么呢
Ha-ha! Fear me, if you dare!
有胆就怕我!
[hisses] Look! A little cat.
看，一只小猫
- Look out, Shrek! He got a piece!
小心，史莱克!他有武器
- lt's a cat, Donkey.Come here, little kitty, kitty.
一只小猫罢了，小猫咪
Come on, little kitty. Come here. Oh! Come here, little kitty.
过来，小猫咪
- Hold on, Shrek! l'm coming! - Come on! Get it off! Get it off!
- 慢着，史莱克，我来了! - 快来，下来!下来!
- Look out, Shrek! Hold still! - Get it off!
- 小心，史莱克!别动! - 走开!
Shrek! Hold still!
史莱克!不要动!
- Did l miss? - No. You got them.
- 我错过了？ - 没有，你打中了
Now, ye ogre, pray for mercy from...
你这个怪物，赶快求饶
Puss... in Boots!
鞋猫剑客
l'll kill that cat!
我要宰了那只猫
- [chuckles] Hairball. - Oh! That is nasty!
- 毛球! - 真恶心
What should we do with him?
我们拿他怎么办？
Take the sword and neuter him. Give him the Bob Barker treatment.
我看我们拿了剑把他当场解决 像电视上那样解决他
Oh, no! Por favor! Please!
妈妈呀!不要!
l implore you! lt was nothing personal, Senor.
求你!这的确是没有什么私人恩怨
l was doing it only for my family. My mother, she is sick. And my father lives off the garbage!
我这样只是为了母亲，她生着病 我父亲靠捡垃圾过日子
The King offered me much in gold and l have a litter of brothers...
国王给我了很多黄金，我兄弟多
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
哇哇哇!
Fiona's father paid you to do this?
费欧娜的父亲给你钱让你对付我
The rich King? Si.
富有的国王，没错
Well, so much for Dad's royal blessing.
不必想皇爸爸的祝福了
Don't feel bad. Almost everybody that meets you wants to kill you.
别难过了 其实每个人见了你都想杀你
Gee, thanks.
谢谢了
Maybe Fiona would've been better off if l were some sort of Prince Charming.
也许费欧娜有了白马王子会更幸福
That's what the King said.
没错，国王也是这么说
Oh, uh... sorry. l thought that question was directed at me.
抱歉 我以为那个问题是要我回答的
Shrek, Fiona knows you'd do anything for her.
费欧娜知道你会为她赴汤蹈火
Well, it's not like l wouldn't change if l could.
我也不是完全不能变
l just... l just wish l could make her happy.
我只是希望能让她幸福
Hold the phone...
等等
''Happiness.''
幸福
''A tear drop away.''
只需要...一滴眼泪
Donkey! Think of the saddest thing that's ever happened to you!
驴子!想想你今生最悲哀的事
Aw, man, where do l begin?
哎哟，让我从哪儿说起呢？
First there was the time that old farmer tried to sell me for some magic beans.
先是有个老农夫 要卖了我换取神奇豆子 我至今未能忘怀
Then this fool had a party
然后这笨蛋跑去派对
and he have the guests trying to pin the tail on me.
所有的客人都想在我身上钉尾巴
Then they got drunk and start beating me with a stick, going ''Pinata!!''
喝醉后用棍子打我 还喊“品尼亚大”
What is a pinata, anyway?
“品尼亚大”是什么意思？
No, Donkey! l need you to cry!
不，驴子，我要你哭
Don't go projecting on me. l know you're feeling bad, but you got to...
不要拿我当你的出气筒 我知道你难过，但是你要自己
You little, hairy, litter-licking sack of...
你这个只会舔垃圾的毛球
What? Is it on? Is it on?
什么？这个开着吗？
This is Fairy Godmother.
我是神仙教母
I'm either away from my desk or with a client.
要么不在 要么有客户
But if you come by the office, we'll be glad to make you an appointment.
你想来我办公室 很高兴于您预约时间
Have a ''happy ever after. ''
祝您幸福快乐
Are you up for a little quest, Donkey?
你准备征战了吗？
That's more like it! Shrek and Donkey, on another whirlwind adventure!
这还差不多 史莱克和驴子的另一场探险
* Ain't no stoppin' us now! Whoo! We're on the move!
谁也不能阻止我们 我们开始行动了
- Stop, Ogre! l have misjudged you. - Join the club. We've got jackets.
- 够了，怪物!我错怪了你 - 一起来，我们有外套
On my honor, l am obliged to accompany you until l have saved your life
不胜荣幸 我很高兴陪伴你，直至拯救你生命
as you have spared me mine.
因为你放过我一次
The position of annoying talking animal has already been taken.
抱歉 多嘴多舌的动物位置已经被占领了
Let's go, Shrek. Shrek?
我们走，史莱克! 史莱克？
- Shrek! - Aw, come on, Donkey. Look at him...
来吧，驴子，你看他
in his wee little boots.
穿着小靴子
You know, how many cats can wear boots? Honestly.
几个猫会穿这种小靴子？
- Let's keep him! - Say what?
- 真的？我们要留下他 - 你说什么？
Listen. He's purring!
听着，他在戏哩呼噜
- Oh, so now it's cute. - Come on, Donkey. Lighten up.
- 蛮可爱的 - 算了，驴子，轻松点
Lighten up? l should lighten up? Look who's telling who to lighten up!
轻松？我应该轻松 看看是谁在要我放轻松
Shrek!
史莱克
Shrek?
They're both festive, aren't they?
两个都有佳节气氛
What do you think, Harold?
你说呢，哈洛？
Um... Yes, yes. Fine. Fine.
都好
Try to at least pretend you're interested in your daughter's wedding ball.
哪怕假装对女儿的 婚礼舞会感兴趣也好
Honestly, Lillian, l don't think it matters.
老实说，莉雅 我并不觉得有什么意义
How do we know there will even be a ball?
怎么会知道要开舞会呢？
Mom. Dad.
妈妈，爸爸
- Oh, hello, dear. - What's that, Cedric? Right! Coming.
- 你好，亲爱的 - 你说什么？西德里克？
Mom, have you seen Shrek?
- 对，来了 - 妈妈，你看到史莱克没有？
l haven't. You should ask your father.
没有，你应该去问你爸爸
Be sure and use small words, dear. He's a little slow this morning.
用词尽量简单，他今早有点迟钝
- Can l help you, Your Majesty? - Ah, yes! Um...
- 需要帮忙吗，陛下？ - 不错
Mmm! Exquisite. What do you call this dish?
精美细致，这道菜叫什么？
That would be the dog's breakfast, Your Majesty.
那是狗儿的早餐，陛下
Ah, yes. Very good, then. Carry on, Cedric.
非常好，继续，西德里克
- Dad? Dad, have you seen Shrek? - No, l haven't, dear.
- 爸爸，你见到史莱克了吗？ - 没有，他肯定跑出去找个
l'm sure he just went off to look for a nice... mud hole to cool down in.
泥洞钻进去冷静头脑
You know, after your little spat last night.
你们昨晚吵过嘴
Oh. You heard that, huh?
你听到了？
The whole kingdom heard you.
乖女儿，整个王国都听见了
l mean, after all, it is in his nature to be...
其实，这就是他的本性
well, a bit of a brute.
是有点兽性
Him?
他？
You know, you didn't exactly roll out the Welcome Wagon.
你也没有铺红地毯来迎接他
Well, what did you expect? Look at what he's done to you.
你还要怎样？ 看他把你弄成什么样子了？
Shrek loves me for who l am.
史莱克爱我
l would think you'd be happy for me.
我以为你会为我高兴
Darling, l'm just thinking about what's best for you.
亲爱的，我不过在想什么对你最好
Maybe you should do the same.
也许你也应该想想
No, really?
不，真的？
Oh, no. That's the old Keebler's place. Let's back away slowly.
不!那是精灵的小屋子 赶快悄悄走开
That's the Fairy Godmother's cottage.
那是神仙教母的屋子
She's the largest producer of hexes and potions in the whole kingdom.
她是本王国 最大的魔法和毒液制造商
Then why don't we pop in there for a spell? Ha-ha! Spell!
我们不如进去拜访她
[Puss in Boots] He makes me laugh.
真会惹人笑
Hi. l'm here to see the...
你好，我是来见
The Fairy Godmother. l'm sorry. She is not in.
神仙教母 抱歉，她不在
Jerome! Coffee and a Monte Cristo. Now!
杰罗姆，马上给我送咖啡和三文治
Yes, Fairy Godmother. Right away.
是，神仙教母，马上就来
Look, she's not seeing any clients today, OK?
她今天不见任何客户
That's OK, buddy. We're from the union.
没关系，我们是工会来的
The union?
工会？
We represent the workers in all magical industries, both evil and benign.
我们代表所有神奇工业的工人 邪恶和仁慈
Oh! Oh, right.
好的
Are you feeling at all degraded or oppressed?
你有受到剥削的感觉吗？
Uh... a little. We don't even have dental.
有一点，我们都没有牙医福利
They don't even have dental.
他们没有牙医福利
Okay, we'll just have a look around.
我们先看看再说
Oh. By the way. l think it'd be better if the Fairy Godmother didn't know we were here.
对了，最好是神仙教母
- Know what l'm saying? Huh? - Huh? Huh? Huh?
不知道我们在此，明白吗？
- Stop it. - Of course. Go right in.
- 停下! - 当然，马上进去
A drop of desire.
一滴欲望
[giggles] Naughty!
淘气
A pinch of passion.
一撮热情
And just a hint of...
还有一点点
lust!
淫欲
- [Shrek] Excuse me. - [gasps] Sorry to barge in like this...
抱歉这么粗鲁闯进来
What in Grimm's name are you doing here?
你们到底想搞什么名堂？
Well,
其实
it seems that Fiona's not exactly happy.Oh-ho-ho!
费欧娜好像并不那么开心
And there's some question as to why that is?
有些问题是需要澄清的
Well, let's explore that, shall we?
那么我们一起来找出原因吧
Ah. P, P, P... Princess. Cinderella.
公主，灰姑娘
Here we are. ''Lived happily ever after.'' Oh...
快乐幸福地生活
[laughs] No ogres!
没有怪物
Let's see. Snow White.
白雪公主
A handsome prince. Oh, no ogres.
有一位英俊王子，没有怪物
Sleeping Beauty. Oh, no ogres!
睡美人，也没有怪物
Hansel and Gretel? No! Thumbelina? No.
汉斯与葛莉泰？没有! 拇指姑娘？没有
The Golden Bird, the Little Mermaid, Pretty Woman...
黄金鸟，美人鱼，小妇人
No, no, no, no, no!
全都没有
You see, ogres don't live happily ever after.
怪物没有幸福生活的故事
All right, look, lady!
好吧，夫人
Don't you point... those dirty green sausages at me!
不许你 拿着肮脏爪子指我!
Your Monte Cristo and coffee.
您的三文治和咖啡
Oh! Sorry.
抱歉
Ah... that's okay. We were just leaving.
没事，反正我们要走了
Very sorry to have wasted your time, Miss Godmother.
抱歉浪费了您的时间，教母
Just... go.
赶快走!
Come on, guys.
来吧!
TGlF, eh, buddy?
还好今天是星期五，对吧？
Working hard or hardly working, eh, Mac?
努力工作要么就不工作
“药房”
Get your fine Corinthian footwear and your cat cheeks out of my face! Man, that stinks!
穿上你的高级皮靴子 别拿你的臭脸在我脸上擦来擦去
You don't exactly smell like a basket of roses.
你也不是像鲜花一样香
- Well, one of these has got to help. - l was just concocting this very plan!
- 总得有人帮忙 - 我只是在协调这个计划
Already our minds are becoming one.
我们已经两脑合一了
Whoa, whoa.
哇哇哇!
lf we need an expert on licking ourselves, we'll give you a call.
需要找人舔身子 我们会给你打电话
Shrek, this is a bad idea.
史莱克，这是个坏主意
Look. Make yourself useful and go keep watch.
别当废物，做点有用的事
Puss, do you think you could get to those on top?
鞋猫，你能够着上面的东西吗？
No problema, boss. ln one of my nine lives,
没问题，老板
l was the great cat burglar of Santiago de Compostela. Ha-ha-ha-ha!
在我今生九条命里 我是西班牙最厉害的猫盗匪
Shrek, are you off your nut?
史莱克，你疯了？
Donkey, keep watch.
驴子，继续放哨
Keep watch? Yeah, l'll keep watch.
放哨？我会放哨
l'll watch that wicked witch come and whammy a world of hurt up your backside.
我会看着邪恶的巫婆下来 说不定打痛你的屁股
l'll laugh, too. l'll be giggling to myself.
我也会笑
- What do you see? - Toad Stool Softener?
- 你能看见什么？ - 蟾蜍粪便软化剂
l'm sure a nice BM is the perfect solution for marital problems.
你说得对，痛快大解一次 肯定是解决婚姻问题的最佳方案
- Elfa Seltzer? - Uh-uh.
抗酸剂
- Hex Lax? - No! Try ''handsome.''
- 通便剂 - 不!试试英俊
Sorry. No handsome.
抱歉，没有英俊
Hey! How about ''Happily Ever After''?
“从此幸福快乐”如何？
Well, what does it do?
有什么功效？
lt says ''Beauty Divine.''
说是美容圣品
ln some cultures, donkeys are revered as the wisest of creatures.
在有些文化中 驴子是最聪明的动物
Especially us talking ones.
尤其是我们会讲话的
Donkey!
驴子
That'll have to do. We've got company.
够了，有人来了
Can we get on with this?
我们可以继续吗？
Hurry!
快点!
Nice catch, Donkey!
好样的，驴子!
Finally! A good use for your mouth.
总算用到你的嘴巴!
Come on!
快点!
* You spurn my natural emotions
* You make me feel like dirt and I'm hurt
* And if I start a commotion
* I run the risk of losing you and that's worse
* Ever fallen in love with someone, ever fallen in love
* In love with someone, ever fallen in love
* In love with someone you shouldn't have fallen in love with
* Ever fallen in love with someone, ever fallen in love
* In love with someone, ever fallen in love
* With someone you shouldn't have fallen in love with
* Fallen in love with
* Ever fallen in love with someone you shouldn't have fallen in love with *
l don't care whose fault it is. Just get this place cleaned up!
我不管是谁的错 快把这里清理干净
Yes  godmother
- 是，神仙教母 - 来人
And somebody bring me something deep fried and smothered in chocolate!
给我拿些油炸食物 上面里着巧克力!
- Mother! - Charming. Sweetheart.
- 母亲! - 小白，乖儿子
This isn't a good time, pumpkin. Mama's working.
现在不行，妈妈要工作
Whoa, what happened here?
哇，这里出了什么事？
- The ogre, that's what!
怪物来过
- What? Where is he, Mom?
什么？他在哪里？
l shall rend his head from his shoulders!
我要把他的头拧下来!
l will smite him where he stands!
当场把他砸扁!
He will rue the very day he stole my kingdom from me!
让他为夺去了我的王国而后悔
Oh, put it away, Junior! You're still going to be king.
收回你的剑，孩子，你还能当上王
We'll just have to come up with something smarter.
我们只需要想出更聪明的主意
Pardon. Um...
对不起
Everything is accounted for, Fairy Godmother, except for one potion. What?
一切都算清楚了 神仙教母 除了一样 - 什么？
l do believe we can make this work to our advantage.
我看这不会对我们有利
''Happily Ever After Potion. Maximum strength.
“从此幸福”汁液最大的能力
''For you and your true love.
对你和你真心爱的人
''lf one of you drinks this, you both will be fine.
如果一人喝下，两人都会没事
''Happiness, comfort and beauty divine.''
幸福，舒适并美丽动人
- You both will be fine? - l guess it means it'll affect Fiona, too.
- 你们两人都会没事 - 恐怕，这也会影响到费欧娜
Hey, man, this don't feel right. My donkey senses are tingling all over.
感觉好像不对 我感觉有点怪怪的
Drop that jug o' voodoo and let's get out of here.
赶快丢掉那瓶鬼东西跑出去
lt says, ''Beauty Divine.'' How bad can it be?
上面写着“美容圣品” 能差到哪里去？
See, you're allergic to that stuff. You'll have a reaction.
你对那种东西过敏 你会产生反应
And if you think that l'll be smearing Vapo Rub over your chest, think again!
如果你觉得 我会给你擦上感冒涂膏，好好想!
Boss, just in case there is something wrong with the potion...
老板，万一那个东西有问题
allow me to take the first sip.
让我先尝尝
lt would be an honor to lay my life on the line for you. Oh, no, no.
我甘愿为你抛洒热血
l don't think so.lf there'll be any animal testing, l'll do it.
不，我看不行 如果要做动物试验，就让我来
That's the best friend's job. Now give me that bottle.
这是好朋友的事，给我瓶子
How do you feel?
你觉得如何？
l don't feel any different. l look any different?
没什么异样，我有变化吗？
You still look like an ass to me.
我看你还是像个驴子
Maybe it doesn't work on donkeys.
也许对驴子没有作用
- Well, here's to us, Fiona. - Shrek?
为我们干杯，费欧娜
- You drink that, there's no going back. - l know.
- 一喝下去就没有退路了 - 我知道
- No more wallowing in the mud? - l know.
- 不在泥潭里打滚了？ - 我知道
- No more itchy butt crack? - l know!
- 后面也不会痒了 - 我知道!
- But you love being an ogre! - l know!
- 但你喜欢当怪物! - 我知道
But l love Fiona more.
但我更爱费欧娜
Shrek, no! Wait!
史莱克，等等!
Got to be... l think you grabbed the ''Farty Ever After'' potion.
一定是 你肯定是拿了“从此放屁”汁液
Maybe it's a dud.
也许失败了
Or maybe Fiona and l were never meant to be.
也许费欧娜和我根本就无缘
Uh-oh. What did l tell you? l feel something coming on.
我不是对你说过吗？ 我觉得好像要出事了
l don't want to die. l don't want to die. l don't want to die!
史莱克，我不想死!
Oh, sweet sister, mother of mercy. l'm melting!
我的妈妈呀!我在熔化!
l'm melting!
我在熔化!
lt's just the rain, Donkey.
下雨而已
Don't worry. Things seem bad because it's dark and rainy
别担心，事情不顺 是因为现在太黑且下雨
and Fiona's father hired a sleazy hitman to whack you.
而且费欧娜的父亲 雇了杀手来对付你
lt'll be better in the morning. You'll see...
早上一切都会好起来
* The sun'll come out...
太阳会出来
* Tomorrow
明天
[yawns] * Bet your bottom... *
以你的屁股担保
Bet my bottom?
以我的屁股担保？
l'm coming, Elizabeth!
我要来了，伊莉莎白!
Donkey?
驴子
Are you all right?
你没事吧？
- Hey, boss. Let's shave him. - D-Donkey?
老板，我们给他剃毛
There you are! We missed you at dinner.
你来了!我们晚餐时没见你
What is it, darling?
怎么了，亲爱的？
Dad... l've been thinking about what you said.
爸爸，我在想你说过的话
And l'm going to set things right.
我要把一切都整理清楚
Ah! Excellent! That's my girl.
好极了，这才是我的乖女儿
lt was a mistake to bring Shrek here.
带史莱克来这里是个错误
l'm going to go out and find him.
我去找他
And then we'll go back to the swamp where we belong.
然后我们就一起回到沼泽地里
[Lillian] Fiona, please!
费欧娜，求你!
Let's not be rash, darling. You can't go anywhere right now.
不要鲁莽 你现在哪里也不能去
Fiona!
费欧娜
Look, l told you he was here. Look at him! Quiet. Look at him.
我说过他在这里，看看他! 安静，别吵醒他!
Good morning, sleepyhead.
- 早上好，瞌睡虫! - 早上好!
Good morning!
早上好
We love your kitty!
我们喜欢你的小猫!
- [Shrek] Oh... My head... - Here, l fetched a pail of water.
- 我的头 - 我打了一桶水
Thanks.
谢谢
A cute button nose?
可爱的小圆鼻子
Thick, wavy locks?
蜷曲的头发？
Taut, round buttocks?
浑圆的屁股？
l'm... l'm...
我
- Gorgeous! - l'll say.
- 太帅了 - 我说是
l'm Jill. What's your name?
我是吉尔，你叫什么？
- Um... Shrek. - Shrek? Wow. Are you from Europe?
- 史莱克 - 史莱克？你是欧洲人吗？
- You're tense. - l want to rub his shoulders.
- 你好紧张 - 我想为他按摩肩膀
- l got it covered. - l don't have anything to rub.
- 我来吧，谢谢 - 我没有什么好按摩
Get in line.
好吧，排队吧
- Have you seen my donkey?
你们看见我的驴子吗？
- Who are you calling donkey?
你们叫谁驴子？
- Donkey? You're a... - A stallion, baby!
- 驴子？你是个 - 牡马
l can whinny. [whinnies] l can count.
我会嘶叫，会数数
Look at me, Shrek! l'm trotting!
看看我，我还会踢前后蹄
That's some quality potion. What's in that stuff?
真是琼浆玉液，里面有什么？
''Oh, don't take the potion, Mr. Boss, it's very bad.''
别喝下汁液，老板，那不好
''Warning: Side effects may include burning, itching, oozing, weeping.
警告，副作用包括燃烧 瘙痒，腹泻，哭泣
''Not intended for heart patients or those with... nervous disorders.''
不适用于有心脏病者或 神经紊乱者
l'm trotting, l'm trotting in place! Yeah!
我可以原地踢前后蹄
What? Senor? ''
- 什么？ - 先生 - 什么？ - 先生
To make the effects of this potion permanent,
如果要能使汁液效果持续
''the drinker must obtain his true love's kiss by midnight.''
喝者必须在子夜前 得到真正爱人的亲吻
Midnight? Why is it always midnight?
子夜？为何总是子夜？
- Pick me! l'll be your true love! - l'll be your true love.
- 选我吧，我当你真爱! - 我来做你真爱
l'll be true... enough.
我要做你的真爱!
Look, ladies, l already have a true love.
小姐们，我已有了真爱
And take it from me, Boss. You are going to have one satisfied Princess.
请记住我的话 你会有一位满意的公主
And let's face it. You are a lot easier on the eyes.
说真的，你现在顺眼多了
lnside you're the same old mean, salty...
但你的内心，还是那个怪物
- Easy. - ...cantankerous, foul,
- 小心点 - 一点没有高雅情绪
angry ogre you always been.
永远愤怒的怪物
And you're still the same annoying donkey.
而你也还是那个令人讨厌的驴子
- Yeah. - [sighs]
对
Look out, Princess. Here comes the new me.
看好了，公主 崭新的我来了
First things first. - We need to get you out of those clothes. - [all gasp]
首先，你要换身衣服
- Ready? - Ready!
- 准备好了？ - 好了
- [Donkey screams] - Driver, stop!
司机，停车!
Oh, God! Help me, please! My racing days are over!
天哪!快帮我 我开快车的日子结束了!
l'm blind! Tell the truth. Will l ever play the violin again?
我是瞎子，说实话 我还能拉小提琴吗？
You poor creature! ls there anything l can do for you?
小可怜，我能帮你吗？
Well, l guess there is one thing.
有一件事
Take off the powdered wig and step away from your drawers.
脱下假发，丢掉裤子!
- Not bad. - Not bad at all.
- 不错嘛! - 一点不错
Father? ls everything all right, Father?
父亲，一切都还好么？
Thank you, gentlemen! Someday, l will repay you.
谢谢，先生，我会偿还的
Unless, of course, l can't find you or if l forget.
除非我找不到你，或是忘了你
你这个带腿的肉蛋 看你怎么过关？
[* Butterfly Boucher: Changes]
* Oh, yeah
* Ch-Ch-Ch-Ch-Changes Turn and face the strange
* Ch-Ch-Changes
* Don't wanna be a richer one
* Ch-Ch-Ch-Ch-Changes
* Turn and face the strange
* Ch-Ch-Changes
* Just gonna have to be a different man
* Time may change me
* But I can't trace time
Halt!
停
Tell Princess Fiona her husband, Sir Shrek, is here to see her.
通报公主她的丈夫前来进见
* Still don't know what I was looking for
* And my time was running wild, a million dead-end streets
* Every time I thought I'd got it made
* It seemed the taste was not so sweet
- [screams] - * Ch-Ch-Ch-Ch-Changes
* Turn and face the strange
费欧娜
- Shrek? - * Ch-Ch-Changes
史莱克
* Don't wanna be a richer one
* Time may change me
* But I can't trace time
Fiona?
费欧娜
Hello, handsome.
你好，帅哥
Shrek!
史莱克
- Princess! - Donkey?
- 公主？ - 驴子？
Wow! That potion worked on you, too?
哇!那个汁液对你也有作用？
What potion?
什么汁液？
Shrek and l took some magic potion. And well...
说来话长，但是 史莱克和我弄到一种神奇汁液
Now, we're sexy!
现在我们就变成性感美人了
Shrek?
史莱克
For you, baby... l could be.
为了你，我愿意
- Yeah, you wish. - Donkey, where is Shrek?
- 想得美 - 驴子，史莱克在哪里？
He went inside looking for you.
他进去找你了
Shrek?
史莱克
Fiona! Fiona!
费欧娜
You want to dance, pretty boy?
想跳舞吗，帅哥？
Are you going so soon? Don't you want to see your wife?
这么快就走？ 不想见见你太太吗？
Fiona?
费欧娜
Shrek?
史莱克
Aye, Fiona. lt is me.
费欧娜，是我
What happened to your voice?
你的声音怎么了？
The potion changed a lot of things, Fiona.
汁液改变了很多东西
But not the way l feel about you.
但不变的是我对你的心
Fiona?
费欧娜
- Charming? - Do you think so?
小白？
[laughs] Dad. l was so hoping you'd approve.
你喜欢吗，爸爸？ 我以为你会同意呢
- Um... Who are you? - Mom, it's me, Shrek.
- 你是谁？ - 妈妈，是我，史莱克
l know you never get a second chance at a first impression,
我知道人的第一印象 永远都是最重要的
but, well, what do you think?
你觉得如何？
[Shrek in distance] Fiona! Fiona!
费欧娜 费欧娜
Fiona!
费欧娜
- Fiona! - Fiona, Fiona! Ho-ho-ho!
Oh, shoot! l don't think they can hear us, pigeon.
走开!他们听不到我们的
Don't you think you've already messed her life up enough?
你不觉得已经 把她的生活搞得够糟了吗？
l just wanted her to be happy.
我只希望她能够幸福
And now she can be.
现在可以了
Oh, sweetheart.
亲爱的
She's finally found the prince of her dreams.
她终于找到了梦寐以求的白马王子
But look at me. Look what l've done for her.
看看我 看我为她所作的改变？
lt's time you stop living in a fairy tale, Shrek.
你不要生活在童话里了
She's a princess, and you're an ogre.
她是公主 你是怪物
That's something no amount of potion will ever change.
这是无法改变的事实
But...
但是
l love her.
我爱她
lf you really love her...
你如果真的爱她
you'll let her go.
就应该让她走
Shrek? Senor.
史莱克？ 先生
What's going on? Where are you going?
怎么回事？你要去哪里？
You wouldn't have had anything to do with this, would you, Harold?
这一切跟你无关吧，哈洛？
* People just ain't no good
人们就是不好 人们就是不好
* I think that's well understood
这个大家都明白
There you go, boys.
给你们了
Just leave the bottle, Doris.
放下瓶子
Hey. Why the long face?
为何那么难过？
lt was all just a stupid mistake.
只不过是个愚蠢的错误
l never should have rescued her from that tower in the first place.
我本来就不该从塔楼里救出她
l hate Mondays.
我讨厌星期一
l can't believe you'd walk away from the best thing that happened to you.
我不相信你竟然要走掉 事情进展那么顺利
What choice do l have?
我有什么办法？
She loves that pretty boy, Prince Charming.
她喜欢那位白马王子
Come on. ls he really that good-looking?
其实，他真有那么英俊吗？
Are you kidding? He's gorgeous!
开什么玩笑，他绝对能迷倒众生
He has a face that looks like it was carved by angels.
他的脸那么棱角分明
- Oh. He sounds dreamy. - You know...
声音如梦如幻
shockingly, this isn't making me feel any better.
可惜我一点感觉都没有
Look, guys. lt's for the best.
这样对大家都好
Mom and Dad approve, and Fiona gets the man she's always dreamed of.
妈妈爸爸同意了 费欧娜得到她梦寐以求的人
Everybody wins.
大家都能赢
Except for you.
除了你
l don't get it, Shrek. You love Fiona. Aye.
我不明白，史莱克 你不是爱费欧娜吗？
And that's why l have to let her go.
所以我要放她走
Excuse me, is she here?
对不起，她在这里吗？
She's, uh... in the back.
她在后面
Oh, hello again.
你们好
Fairy Godmother. Charming.
神仙教母，真是让人高兴
You'd better have a good reason for dragging us down here, Harold.
你最好有原因说明 为何扯大家来这里
Well, l'm afraid Fiona isn't really... warming up to Prince Charming.
我害怕费欧娜并不 那么钟情于白马王子
- FYl, not my fault. - No, of course it's not, dear.
- 其实，也不能怪我 - 当然不会
l mean, how charming can l be when l have to pretend l'm that dreadful ogre?
我还能有多大魅力呢？ 当我假装我是那个可怕的妖怪？
No, no, it's nobody's fault.
不!这不是任何人的错
Perhaps it's best if we just call the whole thing off, okay?
也许最好不要继续下去了
- [both] What? - You can't force someone to fall in love!
- 什么？ - 其实，你不能逼迫人家爱上你
l beg to differ. l do it all the time!
我不同意，我一向这样
Have Fiona drink this and she'll fall in love with the first man she kisses,
让费欧娜喝下这个 她就会爱上最先献吻的人
which will be Charming.
那就是小白
- Umm... no. - What did you say?
- 不 - 你说什么？
l can't. l won't do it.
我不能，我不会那样做
Oh, yes, you will.
你会的，如果你记得
lf you remember, l helped you with your happily ever after.
我成全了你的今生幸福
And l can take it away just as easily.
我也能轻易地拿走
ls that what you want? ls it?
你要这样吗？
- No. - Good boy.
- 不 - 好孩子
Now, we have to go.
我们要走了
l need to do Charming's hair before the ball.
要在舞会前做好小白的头发
He's hopeless. He's all high in the front.
他一点办法没有 前面的头发总是翘起来
He can never get to the back. You need someone to do the back.
你总是需要别人给你做后面
Oh. Thank you, Mother. [Donkey] Mother?
- 谢谢，母亲! - 母亲？
Um... Mary! A talking horse!
玛丽!会说话的驴子!
The ogre!
怪物
Stop them! Thieves! Bandits! Stop them!
阻止他们!有贼，强盗! 阻止他们!
(Announcer) The abs are fab and it's gluteus to the maximus
浑身上下，肌肉发达
here at tonight's Far, Far Away Royal Ball blowout!
在今晚的远的要命王国里
The coaches are lined up as the cream of the crop pours out of them
名人车辆排成行
like Miss Muffet's curds and whey.
出来的有玛菲小姐
Everyone who's anyone has turned out to honor Princess Fiona and Prince Shrek.
大家都互相认识，大家都来 祝福费欧娜公主和史莱克王子
And, oh my, the outfits look gorgeous!
哦，天，他们的打扮真漂亮!
Look! Hansel and Gretel!
看，汉斯与葛莉泰也在!
What the heck are the crumbs for?
面包渣是怎么回事？
And right behind them, Tom Thumb and Thumbelina!
就在他们身后 是拇指汤姆和拇指姑娘
- Oh, aren't they adorable! - [screaming]
他们好可爱
[woman] Here comes Sleeping Beauty!
还有睡美人!
Tired old thing.
可怜的，总是那么累
Who's this? Who's this? Who is this?
这是谁？
Oh. lt's the one, it's the only...
就是她
lt's the Fairy Godmother!
神仙教母
Hello, Far, Far Away!
大家好，远的要命王国!
Can l get a whoop whoop?
大家制造一点气氛吧
May all your endings be happy and...
希望你们都有幸福的结局
Well, you know the rest!
你们知道其他的
We'll be right back with the Royal Far, Far Away Ball
等我们回到远的要命王国 的皇家舞会时
after these messages.
广告过后
l hate these ball shows.
我讨厌这些明星聚会的场合
They bore me to tears. Flip over to Wheel Of Torture!
无聊透了 不如转台看“幸运转轮”
l'm not flipping anywhere, sir, until l see Shrek and Fiona.
没看见史莱克和费欧娜不能转台
Whizzes on you guys.
真讨厌!
Hey, mice, pass me a buffalo wing!
老鼠，给我一个炸鸡翅
No, to your left. Your left!
不，在你的左边
- Tonight on ''Knights''... - Now here's a good show!
- 今晚在“骑士”节目中 - 这是好节目
We got a white bronco heading east into the forest. Requesting backup.
一辆白色勃朗科是向东边树林 请求增援
It's time to teach these madcap mammals
人民卫士要给这些坏人一个教训
their ''devil may mare'' attitudes just won't fly.
- 他们的坏习惯不能逃出法网 - 好了!好了!
Why you grabbing me? Police brutality!
你为何要抓我？员警行为野蛮
l have to talk to Princess Fiona!
我要跟费欧娜公主讲话
- We warned you! - Ow! Ow!
我们警告过你
Did someone let the cat out of the bag?
他们能逃出法网吗？ 还是有人泄密？
You capitalist pig dogs!
- 你，资本主义的猪狗! - 走开!
- Catnip! - That's not mine.
- 猫薄荷! - 那不是我的
Find Princess Fiona!
且慢，找到费欧娜公主! 快来!
l'm a donkey!
我是驴子!
Tell her Shrek... l'm her husband, Shrek!
告诉她我是她的丈夫，史莱克!
骑士!
Quick! Rewind it!
快!倒回磁带
l'm her husband, Shrek! Ow!
告诉她我是她的丈夫，史莱克！
Darling?
亲爱的？
Ah. l thought l might find you here.
我想着能在这里找到你
How about a nice hot cup of tea before the ball?
舞会前喝一杯热茶如何？
l'm not going. The whole Kingdom's turned out to celebrate your marriage.
我不去 但是整个王国都在庆祝你的婚礼
There's just one problem. That's not my husband.
唯一的问题是 那人不是我的丈夫
l mean, look at him.
看看他
Yes, he is a bit different,
他是有点不同，不过
but people change for the ones they love.
人会为了心爱的人而变化
You'd be surprised how much l changed for your mother.
你知道我为了妈妈 怎样变化也会惊奇
Change?
变化？
He's completely lost his mind!
他完全疯了
Why not come down to the ball and give him another chance?
为何不下来给他多一次机会？
You might find you like this new Shrek.
也许你会发现你喜欢新史莱克
But it's the old one l fell in love with, Dad.
但我爱上的是过去的史莱克
l'd give anything to have him back.
我宁肯要回他
Darling. That's mine. Decaf.
亲爱的，那是我的
Otherwise l'm up all night.
低咖啡因，否则我无法睡觉
Thanks.
谢谢!
l got to get out of here!
l got to get out of here! You can't lock us up like this! Let me go!
我要离开这里! 你不能把我们关起来!
What about my Miranda rights?
我的权益呢？ 让我走!
You're supposed to say l have the right to remain silent. Nobody said l have the right to remain silent!
我有权保持沉默!没有人对我讲过
You have the right to remain silent.
你有权保持沉默
What you lack is the capacity.
但你缺乏容量
l must hold on before l, too, go totally mad.
我也要尽量努力不要发疯
Shrek? Donkey?
史莱克，驴子？
Too late.
太迟了
Gingy! Pinocchio! Get us out of here!
姜饼人!小木偶 快救我们出去!
Fire in ze hole!
洞里有火！
Look out below!
看看外面!
Quick! Tell a lie!
快!撒谎!
- What should l say? - Anything, but quick!
- 我要说什么？ - 随便，但是要快
Say something crazy like ''l'm wearing ladies' underwear!''
随便说好像“我穿着女人内裤”
l am wearing ladies' underwear.
我穿着女人内裤
- Are you? - l most certainly am not!
- 有吗？ - 我绝对没有!
lt looks like you most certainly am are!
看来你绝对有!
- l am not! - What kind?
- 我没有! - 哪一种？
- lt's a thong! - Oww! They're briefs!
- 吊带式 - 是男式内裤
- Are not. - Are too!
- 没有 - 有!
- Are not! - Are too!
Here we go. Hang tight.
好了，抓紧
[Donkey] Wait, wait, wait! Ow! Ow! Hey, hey, hey!
等等
- Excuse me? - What? Puss!
- 对不起 - 什么事？鞋猫
Pardon me, would you mind letting me go?
对不起，能让我走吗？
- Sorry, boss. - Quit messing around! We've got to stop that kiss!
- 抱歉，老板 - 不要胡来，我们要阻止那个吻
l thought you was going to let her go.
我以为你会放她走
l was, but l can't let them do this to Fiona.
不错，但我不能 让他们这样待费欧娜
Boom! That's what l like to hear. Look who's coming around!
这样讲话就对了 看看这下谁终于想通了
lt's impossible! We'll never get in. The castle's guarded. There's a moat and everything!
不可能，我们进不去的 城堡有守卫，而且还有护城河!
Folks, it looks like we're up chocolate creek without a Popsicle stick.
看来我们倒霉了 没有冰棒棒
- What? - Do you still know the Muffin Man?
- 什么？ - 你还认识松饼人吗？
Well, sure! He's down on Drury Lane. Why?
当然，他在杜瓦街，怎么？
Because we're gonna need flour.
因为我们要面粉
Lots and lots of flour.
很多很多面粉
Gingy!
姜饼小人
Fire up the ovens, Muffin Man! We've got a big order to fill!
点起烤炉 我们接了大订单，松饼人
“面包店” “杜瓦街”
[Gingy] lt's alive!
它活着
[whinnies] Run, run, run, as fast you can!
跑跑跑，拼命跑
Go, baby, go!
加油，亲爱的
There it is, Mongo! To the castle!
这是大饼，为了城堡
[Shrek] No, you great stupid pastry! Come on!
不，你这个傻子点心
“远巴克咖啡” 快来
[Donkey] Mongo! Down here! Look at the pony!
大饼!下来!来看小马
That's right! Follow the pretty pony!
对呀!快来跟漂亮小马一起玩
Pretty pony wants to play at the castle! [Mongo] Pretty pony.
漂亮的小马想在城堡里玩
Ladies and gentlemen.
女士先生们
Presenting Princess Fiona and her new husband, Prince Shrek.
呈现费欧娜公主和新婚丈夫 史莱克王子
Shrek, what are you doing?
史莱克，你做什么呢？
l'm just playing the part, Fiona.
我只在扮演角色
ls that glitter on your lips?
你抹了亮唇蜜？
Mm. Cherry flavored. Want to taste?
樱桃味的，你要尝尝吗？
- Ugh! What is with you? - But, Muffin Cake...
- 你怎么回事？ - 不过，亲爱的
C Minor, put it in C Minor.
C降调
Ladies and gentlemen.
女士先生们
l'd like to dedicate this song to...
我要把这首歌献给
Princess Fiona and Prince Shrek.
费欧娜公主和史莱克王子
Fiona, my Princess.
费欧娜，尊贵的公主
Will you honor me with a dance?
愿意赏脸共舞吗？
* Where have all the good men gone
好男人都去了哪里？
* And where are all the gods? [all chant] Dance!
所有神仙都去了哪里？
* Where's the streetwise Hercules
大力神去了哪里？
* To fight the rising odds?
应战坏人
Since when do you dance?
你从几时开始跳舞了？
Fiona, my dearest, if there's one thing l know,
费欧娜，亲爱的 我只知道
it's that love is full of surprises.
爱情充满了惊奇
* Late at night I toss and I turn
夜深沉，难入眠
* And I dream of what I need
我梦中见到自己向往
Hit it!
表演
* I need a hero
我向往英雄
All right, big fella! Let's crash this party!
大家伙，我们去闯舞会了
Man the catapults!
上弹弓
Aim! Fire!
预备，射!
- Brace yourselves! - Ooh! Purty!
- 振作精神! - 漂亮
Not the gumdrop button!
不要那个胶扣子!
lncoming!
进入!
Ha-ha! All right!
好耶!
* Somewhere after midnight In my wildest fantasy
子夜过后 在我的魔幻中
Go, Mongo! Go!
大饼!去!
Man the cauldrons!
准备大锅炉
After you, Mongo.
您先请
- That's it! Heave-ho! - Watch out!
- 对!加油!吭唷! - 小心!
Shrek!
史莱克
More heat, less foam!
多加热量，少些泡沫
* Up where the mountains Meet the heavens above
在山上能触到天堂
* Out where the lightning Splits the sea
闪电将海水分开
* I could swear there is someone Somewhere watching me
我发誓有人在看着我们
Heave! Ho!
加油吭唷! 加油!
No...!
不
Come on!
加油
Look out!
看
- Be good. - [weeping bitterly]
听话!
[sobbing] He needs me! Let me go!
他需要我!让我走!
我向往英雄
Donkey!
驴子!
Puss!
鞋猫!
Go! Go! Your lady needs you! Go!
快去!女士需要你
Today, l repay my debt.
今天，我还清债务
[growling] On guard!
守卫!
* He's gotta be strong And he's gotta be fast
他强壮又神速
* And he's gotta be fresh From the fight
刚刚从战场征战回来
- * I need a hero *
我期待英雄
- Stop!
停!
- Hey, you! Back away from my wife. - Shrek?
你，远离我的妻子!
You couldn't just go back to your swamp and leave well enough alone.
你原可以滚回沼泽泥潭 大家就都能平安无事
- Now! - Pigs und blanket!
- 快! - 小猪和毯子
Pinocchio! Get the wand!
小木偶!快拿魔术棒!
l see London! l see France!
我见过伦敦和巴黎!
l'm a real boy!
我是真正的小男孩
Catch!
抓住
Donkey!
驴子!
l'm a real boy. Aah!
我是真正的小男孩
That's mine!
那是我的
Pray for mercy, from Puss... And Donkey!
赶快求饶 求鞋猫和驴子放过你
She's taken the potion! Kiss her now!
她拿去了汁液!快点亲吻
No!
不
- Fiona. - Shrek.
史莱克
Harold! You were supposed to give her the potion!
你应该给她汁液
Well, l guess l gave her the wrong tea.
恐怕给她倒错了茶!
- [Charming] Mommy!
母亲!
- Mommy?
母亲？
[growls] l told you.
我说过
Ogres don't live happily ever after.
怪物不可能有幸福快乐的生活
[gasping] Oh, Dad!
爸爸
- ls he...? - Yup.
- 他是否？ - 是的
He croaked.
他叫了一声
Harold? Dad?
- 哈洛？ - 爸爸？
l'd hoped you'd never see me like this.
我很不愿意你看到我这样
- And he gave you a hard time! - Donkey!
他让你日子不好过
No, no, he's right. l'm sorry.
不，他是对的，抱歉
To both of you. l only wanted what was best for Fiona.
我只是为了费欧娜的幸福
But l can see now... she already has it.
但我能看出已经找到了
Shrek, Fiona...
史莱克，费欧娜
Will you accept an old frog's apologies...
你们能不能接受 一只老青蛙的道歉？
and my blessing?
我的祝福？
Harold? l'm sorry, Lillian. l just wish l could be the man you deserve.
抱歉，莉雅 我只想成为配得上你的男人
You're more that man today than you ever were... warts and all.
你向来就是个男子汉 除了缺陷外
Boss! The Happily Ever After Potion!
老板!  “从此幸福”汁液
Midnight!
子夜时分，费欧娜
Fiona. ls this what you want?
这是你想要的吗？
To be this way forever?
永远这样？
- What? - Because if you kiss me now...
- 什么？ - 因为如果你现在吻我
we can stay like this.
我们可以永远这样
You'd do that?
你会愿意吗？
- For me? - Yes.
- 为了我？ - 是的
l want what any princess wants.
我想要每个公主都想要的
To live happily ever after...
永远幸福快乐
with the ogre l married.
跟我嫁的怪物在一起
Whatever happens, l must not cry!
无论发生什么事，我都不能哭!
You cannot make me cry!
你不要惹我哭!
新婚快乐!
[laughs] Hey. You still look like a noble steed to me.
你还像个高贵的牡马
[giggles] Now, where were we?
刚才到哪里了？
Oh. l remember.
记起来了
Hey! lsn't we supposed to be having a fiesta?
难道不要开派对吗？
Uno, dos, cuatro, hit it!
一，二，四
Puss and Donkey, y'all...
鞋猫和驴子
* She's into superstitions
* Black cats and voodoo dolls
- Sing it, Puss! - * I feel a premonition
* That girl's gonna make me fall
Here we go! * She's into new sensations
来呀!
* New kicks in the candlelight
* She's got a new addiction
* For every day and night
* She'll make you take your clothes off
* And go dancing in the rain
* She'll make you live her crazy life
* But she'll take away your pain
* Like a bullet to your brain
* Upside inside out
* Living la vida loca
Hey gorgeous!
他做了什么？
* Living la vida loca
* Her lips are devil red
* And her skin's the color of mocha
* She will wear you out
- * Living la vida loca - [Donkey] She livin' it loca!
* Living la vida loca
- [Donkey] Say it one more time now! - * Living the vida loca
大家一起来!
[Puss in Boots] Hey, Donkey, that's Spanish!
再唱一遍
* She'll push and pull you down
* Living la vida loca
* She will wear you out
* She'll push and pull you down
* Living the vida loca
* Her lips are devil red
* And her skin's the color of mocha
* She will wear you out
* Living la vida loca
* Living la vida loca *
* All by myself * All by myself
自己来 自己来
* Don't wanna be
不要自己单独
* All by myself anymore... *
形单影只
Amigo, we are off to the Kit-Kat Club. Come on, join us.
朋友们，大家一起去热闹夜总会
Thanks, compadre. l'm... l'm not in the mood.
谢谢，好朋友 我没有情绪
We will cheer you up! Find you a nice burro!
我们替你开心 给你找个女朋友
Hey, baby!
辣妹妹
Hey, that's my girl! Yeah! All right!
那才是我的女生!
Baby, where you been?
你去了哪里？
- [cries] - l'm sorry, too. l should've stayed. But Shrek had this thing he had to do.
抱歉，我本该留下来 但是史莱克有重要事做
What? Say it one more time.
什么？再说一遍
What you talking about? Are you serious?
你在讲什么？你没开玩笑吧？
- Papa!
爸爸
Look at our little mutant babies!
看看我们的变种小宝宝
[Donkey] l got to get a job.
我要找份工作